[
  {
    "question": "I would like to know if the duas made in the masjid Al Haram and in the Masjid of Madina are more likely to be accepted?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAjWtkAtT7L/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Sheikh is beard transplant halal. I've never grown a beard although i am of age? What is the ruling?",
    "answer": "This is not required at all. Allah has asked men to leave the beard and not touch it, He did not ask to grow it thick or long! Whatever comes naturally is sufficient.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAjDYRENbfa/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If I paint a kaafir's house knowing that he's paining his house for celebrating his pagan festival. Is it supporting in shirk?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAi3vbftU8h/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If a man asks a father to marry his daughter, but the father doesn't approve and therefore doesn't even tell his daughter that the man asked in the first place, to which she might have otherwise said yes, is the father wrong for not telling his daughter?",
    "answer": "No, he is not wrong as this is his right to refuse even if his daughter would have been fine with it.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAiD75zN_OY/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it permissible for a woman to work as a cashier, receptionist in islam?",
    "answer": "If she is abiding by the proper hijab and the Islamic etiquette, this is permissible when needed.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAfdAZkNFTJ/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When a woman is on her menses, is she allowed to recite parts of the Quran as part of her daily adkhar, like the 3 Quls and Ayat al Kursi?",
    "answer": "She can do that without any problem. SHe can also recite the whole Quran without holding the Quran. She can do that from memory or through her mobile phone or a book of tafseer.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAeMblIteou/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I used to neglect my sunnah prayers before and after duhr but have been praying sunnahs on the other prayers, is this permissible? Will I be sinful for missing sunnah prayers?",
    "answer": "You are not sinful for that but you have lost rewards for it.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAdthDyNmCq/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are our duas/repentance still accepted when we're on our periods?",
    "answer": "It's valid to make duas and repentance during period, there's no problem in this whatsoever.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAdWMhANBTX/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If we are praying sunnah and in between that farz salah is started, Then it is mandatory to leave the sunnah immediately and join farz Salah?",
    "answer": "If you can quickly finish it before the imam starts the prayer, do that. But if you estimate that he will give his first takbeer before you completing your sunnah, break it and join the imam.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAc45Q4tUCD/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can an ordinary person perform Ruqyah on themselves or others, or is it necessary to be an imam?",
    "answer": "The best ruqya is the one you perform on yourself.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAb5VvKtAwU/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can we combine dhuhr and asr at dhuhr time?",
    "answer": "You can do that if there is a legitimate Islamic reason such as travelling or rain.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAbALDYNz6Y/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What to do if Islam is mocked in class at school in a non-Muslim country like France? If I don't react, am I considered a disbeliever?",
    "answer": "You should defend Islamto the best of your ability. After all it is a democracy and you have the freedom of speech, so they claim!",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAan4ITNAg1/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When were the Islamic months first established? Or these were already there when Prophet Mohammad (ﷺ) was born?",
    "answer": "Correct. Such lunar months were there before the birth of the prophet salla Allahu alaihi wa sallam and continued to be there till date.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAahxE0NCkA/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can a Muslim woman remove her hijab in front of non Muslim women?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAaY1sbt3kO/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can we use soap and shampoo while making ghusl?",
    "answer": "It is best to either wash yourself with soap and shampoo first then take ghusl or take ghusl first and then shampoo yourself.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAY2Pr4tH2C/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Sheikh, is double chin considered as awrah?",
    "answer": "Yes, for women.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAYiUN1tLS_/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "My concern is, can we play the recitation of some verses from the Quran on some audio device and indulge in some other (halal) work. Knowing that at times we may lose concentration upon the Verses that are being recited. Is this permissible?",
    "answer": "As long as you are attentive most of the time, this is fine. Otherwise, do not put it on.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAX0s0QNUy8/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How can one get over the guilt of past sins? If we are at a point where it hurts, and we even feel hatred for ourselves every time we remember committing them, even though we know that Allah is the Most Merciful and Forgiving.",
    "answer": "This is satan messing up with your head to deprive you from enjoying life and make you stuck forever in your guilt, feeling despair of Allah's which is worse than your original sin.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAWvU9UNxuJ/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Sheikh nowadays it has become difficult for a girl to marry cuz there are so many women and less men. Then how can girls marry?",
    "answer": "This is, like all different types of provisions; in the hands of Allah. Many girls get married when Allah wills it. Some marry more than once. Others may marry a married man and accept to be a co wife.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://instagram.com/p/DAWq9BMtx3m/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Islam ruling on women vlogging their lifestyle on YouTube? Is it permissible or not.",
    "answer": "This is totally prohibited.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAWC46ktrRC/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If I am wearing kufi andf say that wearing kufi takes that charm away if I am wearing some good looking branded clothes. Is this kufr?",
    "answer": "Why would it be kufr? Kufr is disbelief or mocking Islam. Kufi is not even part of Islam! You can make fun of it without any problem.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAVG4nSt1L9/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it permissible when I reciting Quran I rest the Quran over my lap? Or when I'm lying, resting the Quran in the bed?",
    "answer": "No problem.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAUYATWIP_n/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is using the word “unfortunately” permissible?",
    "answer": "Fortunately, this is permissible.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://instagram.com/p/DATf0njNt_E/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Shaikh if someone says shahadah for apostasy without remorse feeling, will he be a muslim again?",
    "answer": "Remorse is one of the pillars of repentance without which the repentance is not valid.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DATKgqitqMK/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If a muslim man applies make up to make the face look like a skull is it permissible?",
    "answer": "This is imitating the disbelievers in their festivals such as Halloween and this is totally prohibited and a major sin.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DARKaI0NLuT/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If a girl is not able to grow affection for her husband even after marriage and only for the sake of her deen she's forcing herself to like him. Will she be sinful to ask for a khula from her husband merely on the basis of not being able to like him?",
    "answer": "If she is unable to give him his rights and has a great resentment for him, she is not sinful for getting a khulu.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAPKIhLND4I/"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Sheikh, is there any legit islamic way to understand the meanings of dreams? As example, my mother has been dreaming of black dogs multiple times recently. Is that pure coincidence an with no meaning?",
    "answer": "Any dream one has that he wakes up from afraid, intimidated or depressed, this is from satan as stated by our Prophet salla Allah alaihi wa sallam.",
    "sources": [
      {
        "grade": "Assim Al-Hakeem (Grade #4)",
        "link": "https://www.instagram.com/p/DAOJmzuNtsZ/"
      }
    ]
  }
]
